I had my girlfriend
bake some apple pie.
Want some?
Roy...
As you can see,
this is that which is forbidden.
I may not know alchemy,
but I do know one thing!
Those who commit
that which is forbidden...
Don't worry.
I haven't done a thing.
But you were planning to try?
So many died—
I mean, I killed them.
It was war.
You weren't there.
Oh, right. If you couldn't stand
going to war and killing the enemy,
you should have chosen
duty at the rear, like I did.
By becoming a State Alchemist
and then calling even some of
those people back to this world,
did you think it would save you?!
Good question.
Is performing the forbidden so straightforward
that you can just cram for it
to be able to pull it off?!
Or did you just want to die?
If that's the case, there are easier ways to go about it.
As it turns out, I was unable to attempt it,
out of fear for my own life.
Of course you couldn't.
That's just the kind of person I am.
That's true about anyone.
However, there is a better way to use the life I have than this.
Maes,
I've made up my mind.
Tell me more, Roy.
Lt. Colonel?
Um, Lt. Colonel?
It's okay. I'll wait.
Führer!
You seem to be investigating
the higher levels of the military, huh?
Y-Yes, in regards to the 5th Laboratory.
Regarding that matter,
I took charge of it personally and concluded it's possible that Brig. Gen. Basque Grand
teamed up with Ishbalan radicals in conducting seditious research.
Are you dissatisfied with that?
Well, I, uh... Yes.
Oh, is this about
the Philosopher's Stone?
Yes. It can be surmised that within the military,
there was experimentation with creating Philosopher's Stones
and that there were various
illegal actions taken to that end.
And it was not all carried out
at Brig. Gen. Grand's discretion.
At the very least,
this also falls upon the succession of superior officers over Doctor Marcoh.
It's possible that these
persons were complicit.
Major generals,
brigadier generals, colonels...
Involved in something like this?
Yes. In just the last year, each one has either died or gone missing.
However, when you consider that
the 5th Laboratory was still operating
and that just the other day,
Ishbalan refugees were attacked
by someone within the military who employed mercenaries...
You're saying that even now,
some power within the military
is attempting to create a Philosopher's Stone?
If something like that
ever came to light,
the military would lose its authority!
I'm joking! Follow through on it.
After all, someone has been conducting prohibited, top-secret human experimentation
and then using assassins who call themselves homunculi to wipe out the evidence.
I cannot overlook such an outrage.
We will purge this corruption.
Thank you very much.
As such, Führer...
Mm, Doctor Marcoh, right?
I'd like to question him for information again.
Juliet...
I will ask that he be brought to Central immediately.
The truth is, she's the only one who knows where Marcoh is hiding.
It's a precaution to prevent me from revealing anything, even if tortured by the enemy.
Very well, if you please...
uh... Douglas-san.
We will purge this corruption.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
In other words,
this means that all the bigwigs who are connected with the 5th Laboratory
either die or turn up missing?
And there weren't any criminals on the list who had the Uroboros mark on them.
It sounds like they're talking about some scary stuff.
I don't want to stick my nose into any more trouble.
Well, there should still be scientists who worked under Doctor Marcoh.
If we could find some of them...
Well, leave that to me.
Um, about that...
It's like it doesn't
really matter anymore.
What are you guys talking about?!
We're saying,
we've had enough of the Philosopher's Stone and homunculi and other dicey stuff like that.
And that maybe, it would be smarter to look for a different method.
That would definitely be smarter.
But if you could find it that simply, there wouldn't be any sport in it.
There is one person who might know something about it.
Our teacher.
She lives to the south,
in a place called Dublith.
We plan on paying her a visit.
Elric brothers...
Here, just one stop before Dublith!
Is there something there?
It's the holy land of
Automail mechanics, Rush Valley!
I've always wanted to go there!
Take me with you! Take me with you! Take me with you! Take me with you!
Go there by yourself.
But who's going to pay
my traveling expenses?
You're trying to mooch off of us?!
It's okay, isn't it?
It's on the way, and all.
What's the use?
Yay!
So those two have finally decided not to get involved in any more dangerous business, huh?
They must have realized how hard it was for us to guard them.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
If that were the case,
what fun would that be?
This is all to keep us from
becoming the next victims.
Pretty sharp for a kid.
You're not going to Dublith?!
But we are going as far as Rush Valley.
In that case, okay.
But why not?
Weren't you going to ask your teacher
about other methods besides the Philosopher's Stone?
If we did that, we'd be killed.
Killed?
We never told our teacher about becoming State Alchemists.
Not to mention that if it got out that
we had performed human transmutation...
I'd like to live a little bit longer.
I would at least like to have fallen in love, Brother.
And even if that weren't the case,
I get the feeling we shouldn't ask our teacher about this.
So, what are you going to do?
There's a large-scale Ishbalan camp in the mountains to the south.
I'm guessing that Scar and
the others are headed there.
You're going after Scar?
It's said that a Philosopher's Stone was once created at Ishbal.
But since they never had alchemy introduced to them in the first place,
we think it might be possible that they
created it in a completely different manner.
I'm going to pound on him
and make him tell us the secret.
Now, Brother, he really isn't that bad a person.
He's a killer.
And he uses alchemy to do it.
I can't let him
get away with that.
Brother! Master!
Hey.
Who are you?! You are not of the people of Ishbal, are you?
Oh, how rude of me.
I've failed to introduce myself.
I'm the State Alchemist in charge of exterminating this region.
You've got a visitor!
Master!
I'm so glad you are safe.
I'm impressed that
you survived as well.
Where have you been up to now?
There are a certain number of us
living in the mountains to the south.
We were planning on
visiting there ourselves.
Our countrymen who were in Central were coming to meet us,
traveling so as not to catch the military's attention,
when along the way,
they heard stories about you.
In these last three years,
they say you've been going around killing State Alchemists.
It was State Alchemists who burned down our villages.
I can understand your
feelings of resentment.
It's true!
These guys are Ishbalans, aren't they?
Are you sure it's safe to be
hanging around in a place like this?
Aren't you guys supposed to be living in the designated camps?
But what you are doing is taking out
your anger in sworn vengeance, is it not?
Vengeance only sows the seeds of renewed vengeance.
In the ancient words of Ishbala, it says:
"Those who receive pain can still sleep."
"Those who give pain cannot sleep."
That arm of yours...
Is that your brother's arm?
Why didn't you report to me that the
Elric brothers had been put in a hospital?
Huh? Didn't I mention that? Well, it's no big deal.
Never mind them,
No big deal?!
it sounds like your posting to Central is going to be formally settled on.
Hurry up and make yourself important
so you can make things easier for the rest of us.
And find yourself a wife!
Be gentle with the telephone.
Lieutenant, get us a train.
To Central?
Something is going on.
Mustang-san is just
worried about those two.
There's no need to
worry him unnecessarily,
nor does he need to know
about any of the nonsense.
For one thing, it's possible that our phones are being tapped.
Sorry, but I still have
things to look into.
Okay, be careful.
Papa still has lots of work to do.
I'll be back later.
Bring me the materials
on the Liore riots!
Right!
Where are the diagrams of the
transmutation circles from the 5th Laboratory?!
The budget from the first year of the Ishbal Rebellion!
Am I going to get
overtime pay for this?
I'll give you a picture of Elicia!
Ishbal... Liore... Mugear's mines...
Once they got near a Philosopher's Stone,
they were destroyed.
Strange, isn't it?
If they're driving people to
create a Philosopher's Stone,
why would they spread stories around
that destruction befalls those who seek the Philosopher's Stone?
Is it to get rid of all the evidence?
No... It couldn't be...
just the opposite, could it?
Supposing everything was reversed...
Hold on... The unit that caused
the outbreak of war in Ishbal was...
...Douglas? Where have
I heard that name before?
Um, there's a phone call
from the Führer's secretary.
Yes, Doctor Marcoh has arrived in Central.
He is waiting at the hotel.
Thank you very much.
I will go see him right away.
Douglas... Juliet...
Scieszka! Put all of these materials back where you found them!
Once that's done, you can go home!
Also, you're fired!
Don't ever come around here again.
Sorry to put you
through all this trouble.
Ms. Secretary... Douglas-san,
do you know much
about the Ishbalan War?
No, I have always had desk jobs.
So have I, you know?
I've been looking into
some things lately.
Did you know that the reason the rebellion broke out
was that one of the soldiers stationed there recklessly shot and killed an Ishbalan child?
That soldier's name,
it turns out, was Juliet Douglas.
It's a common name.
That's where it gets interesting. The soldier with that name
was supposed to have died two years before the Ishbal Rebellion.
That is odd.
There's one other "odd" thing.
Douglas was dead before then.
And yet the muster roll for this person
named Juliet Douglas was never withdrawn.
On the contrary,
over the last two years,
the soldier with that name
has been suddenly promoted.
And now, she has been promoted to the Führer's Ministerial Secretary?
Who are you?
Were you at Ishbal?
Or did you just use Douglas's
registration to get into the military?
The Doctor is waiting.
Is that even Marcoh
behind that door?
Nice to meet you.
Or perhaps, "farewell"
might be more appropriate.
That's a cool tattoo
you've got there, sweetheart.
Lt. Colonel!
That was unexpectedly skillful, huh?
Sloth, make sure to let everyone know.
Lieutenant Ross,
they're right next to the Führer!
The enemy has fully infiltrated the military. Their purpose...
is not to create a Philosopher's Stone.
No...
Come with me.
Yes, sir.
Ah, dammit...
Jeez, what a pain...
What? He's not there?!
He left for Central with Lieutenant Hawkeye.
Has something happened?
With this information,
he had a chance to rise
right to the top!
In any event, we should get to someplace safe.
You're right. It's not as though
I've got nothing left to hang onto.
Why don't you
tell me all about it?
The Lieutenant has a mole under one of her eyes.
Is that right?
I must have gotten careless.
That's amazing.
Forgive me.
I have a wife and daughter waiting for me at home.
That was a pretty good act,
wasn't it, Lt. Colonel Hughes?
I'm going to become the Führer.
I'm going to change
the way this country runs.
That's the only thing I can do.
Then you'll need someone who
understands you and can support you.
Someone underneath you, who can push you upward.
Mama, why? Why are they burying Papa?
Huh? Why are those men burying Papa?
Why?
Elicia...
I don't want them to.
I don't want them to!
If they do that, then Papa
can't do his work anymore!
Mama, stop them!
Elicia...
Papa said he still had
a lot of work to do!
I don't want them to!
Don't bury him! Mama!
Papa! Papa!
Killed in the line of duty and
posthumously promoted two ranks...
Brigadier General Hughes, huh?
What am I going to do
now that the man who said
he would stay beneath me and assist me
has gone above me, you idiot?
Colonel...
Once, I tried putting together a theory
on how to perform human transmutation.
Just now, I was frantically remembering it.
We alchemists are nasty creatures.
If the Elric brothers
were mixed up in this,
why didn't he report it to me?
He didn't have to go
charging into this alone.
Haven't you figured it out yet?
Figured what out?
When it comes to those brothers,
the Colonel has been known to
lose his level-headed judgment.
And so, Brigadier General Hughes
took everything concerning
the Elric brothers upon himself,
so that the Colonel could relax
and set his sights above himself.
It's starting to rain, huh?
Yes.
I wonder if this is like the food that Mom used to make.
Hughes-san, his wife, and Elicia-chan were all such fine people.
Uh-huh.
Lt. Colonel Hughes is a mother hen and a busybody. He bothers me.
He always used to come to joke around with us, huh?
Every day, he said
he was busy with work,
but he still always
came by to check on us.
I wonder why he looked after us
as much as he did.
Who knows?
When we get back to Central, make sure you thank him.
Ed?
Is something the matter, Brother?
Nope.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 26: "Her Reason"
I never even thought about it.
Could there be somebody
who felt that way about me?